Yahor Labanau

QA Engineer with 2 years of commercial experience, mainly focused on functional web testing and developing comprehensive maintainable test-cases. I will make a great addition to the team due to being proactive, focusing on solving business issues and willing to embrace lifelong learning. Looking for a remote position or relocation opportunities with a possibility to gain commercial experience in QA Automation to also help improve the automation quality of the projects I'm going to contribute to.

yahorlabanau@gmail.com

t.me/lawb4

Minsk, Belarus

github.com/lawb4

RESPONSIBILITIES

- · Functional/Non-Functional requirements analysis before writing checklists for each story
- Identification of the issues' priority, severity, influence on the related functionality
- Development and maintenance of test documentation (test-cases, checklists, bug reports, test result reports)
- Test-cases' peer review
- Providing demo sessions for team members and customers
- · Working according to Agile (Scrum) workflow with corresponding events
- Support releases
- Build deployment
- · Web services and API testing
- · Validating data in databases

EXPERIENCE

EPAM Systems

Software Testing Engineer

10/2020 - Present

- Project 1: Belarusian Volleyball Federation (Web Application)
- Project 2: Learning Portal (Web Application) learn.epam.com
- Project 3: Employee 1-2-1 Evaluation Module (part of Internal Employee Feedback Portal Web Application)
- Project 4: Employee Feedback Portal (Internal Web Application)

Volunteering: The 2nd European Games 2019

Front Desk Representative

05/2019 - 06/2019

· Providing assistance and necessary information to English and Spanish speaking guests

ACHIEVEMENTS

EPAM Systems: Learning Portal (Web Application) - learn.epam.com

- · As one of the most domain-knowledgeable testers, I onboarded and mentored 3 junior testers to produce faster and deeper immersion into the project workflow. This process allowed them to be of value to the customer as early as possible, and helped me to develop the necessary leadership skills.
- · I proposed an improvement to the Regression Testing flow, which allowed to conduct testing more effectively and leave a few more hours for other
- I was responsible for ensuring communication between our team and DevOps engineers regarding the deployment of the application builds. This activity helped to ensure our Test Lead had more spare time to bring more value to the project in terms of leadership and provided me with an insight into some DevOps procedures.
- I improved our project's documents with new UML diagrams reflecting the latest changes in the workflow regarding individual interfaces and components of the application. This allowed our external users (and team members) to deepen their knowledge about our application's workflow, which made it easier to navigate and use, leaving positive feedback for the application.
- · When our Test Lead was overwhelmed with leadership activities, I used to help her to write test result reports after the application's release. Those reports helped the whole team understand the current pain points in our application and further ways to address them.
- I composed a dozen SQL-based exercises, so that new team members could practice using SQL queries in the scope of our application. Not only did it enable them to improve their SQL practical abilities, it also allowed to get to know the application's structure better and bring value to the project sooner.

EPAM Systems: Non-Project Achievements

In terms of the company's non-project activities, I contributed to the translation of the "JavaScript Automation Practice" group's educational materials into English. This way, I brought some value to the company by helping to release the materials to the English-speaking audience.

API Testing

EDUCATION

Minsk State Linguistic University (MSLU)

Bachelor of Linguistics, English and Spanish languages Teaching

2016 - 2021

(No)SQL

Self-Education

- · RedRover AQA School (redrover.school)
- · Testing: EPAM Functional Testing Mentoring Program
- Java: javarush.com (codegym.cc)
- MOOC.fi platform: Java Programming
- · Alan Richardson: Java for Testers

Functional Testing

- JetBrains Academy: Java for Beginners Track
- · JavaScript: EPAM JavaScript for Testers Program

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

· Web: HTTP(S), TCP/IP, HTML, CSS, DevTools, Fiddler

- API: SOAP/REST, Swagger, Postman, SoapUI
- CI/CD: GitHub, GitLab, Jenkins, TeamCity
- · Databases: Microsoft SQL Server, PostgreSQL, MongoDB
- Programming Languages: Java, JavaScript
- Automation Testing: JUnit
- Soft skills: endeavoring, meticulous, indomitable